[
  {
    "Question": "A ________ can either be malware or hardware. The main purpose of this malware is to record the keys pressed by a user on the keyboard.",
    "OP1": "Keyloggers",
    "OP2": "Rootkit",
    "OP3": "Worm",
    "OP4": "Trojan",
    "Answer": 1
  },
  {
    "Question": "A ________ port transmits one bit of a byte at a time as a single stream of bits. It is meant for transmitting slow data over long distances.",
    "OP1": "Parallel",
    "OP2": "Universal Serial Bus",
    "OP3": "Serial",
    "OP4": "Display",
    "Answer": 3
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is also known as a flash drive?",
    "OP1": "Disk Array",
    "OP2": "HDD",
    "OP3": "SSD",
    "OP4": "Pen drive",
    "Answer": 4
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following keyboard shortcut is used to close a MS-Word 365 document?",
    "OP1": "Ctrl + F3",
    "OP2": "Alt + F3",
    "OP3": "Alt + F4",
    "OP4": "Shift + F5",
    "Answer": 3
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which among the following is incorrect about cache memory?",
    "OP1": "It is slower than the main memory.",
    "OP2": "It keeps the programs that can be run in a short amount of time.",
    "OP3": "It acts as a high speed buffer between CPU and main memory.",
    "OP4": "It stores data in temporary use.",
    "Answer": 1
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which among the following keyboard shortcut can be used to open Windows Explorer?",
    "OP1": "Windows Key + E",
    "OP2": "Windows Key + R",
    "OP3": "Windows Key + X",
    "OP4": "Windows Key + W",
    "Answer": 1
  },
  {
    "Question": "A ________ is a networking device that filters network traffic while connecting multiple computers or communicating devices.",
    "OP1": "Repeater",
    "OP2": "Distributor",
    "OP3": "Switch",
    "OP4": "Router",
    "Answer": 3
  },
  {
    "Question": "________ server acts as a set of components accessible to the software developer through an API defined by the platform itself.",
    "OP1": "Application",
    "OP2": "Mail",
    "OP3": "File Transfer Protocol (FTP)",
    "OP4": "Database",
    "Answer": 1
  },
  {
    "Question": "A ________ is a contagious program or code that attaches itself to another piece of software and then reproduces itself when that software is run.",
    "OP1": "Trojan",
    "OP2": "virus",
    "OP3": "adware",
    "OP4": "spyware",
    "Answer": 2
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which among the following keyboard shortcuts open the properties for the selected item on a Windows 10 home screen?",
    "OP1": "Alt + Shift + Spacebar",
    "OP2": "Ctrl + Shift + Spacebar",
    "OP3": "Alt + Enter",
    "OP4": "Ctrl + Enter",
    "Answer": 3
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following shortcut key is used to quickly create a new, blank workbook in MS-Excel 2010?",
    "OP1": "Ctrl + N",
    "OP2": "Alt +shift + W",
    "OP3": "Alt + shift +N",
    "OP4": "Ctrl + W",
    "Answer": 1
  },
  {
    "Question": "________ is a reading device that reads printed text by scanning it character by character.",
    "OP1": "Track Ball",
    "OP2": "Digitizer",
    "OP3": "Magnetic Ink Card Reader (MICR)",
    "OP4": "Optical Character Reader (OCR)",
    "Answer": 4
  },
  {
    "Question": "Consider the following statement about the MATCH () function of MS-Excel 2010:<br>P: It searches for a specified item in a range of cells, and then returns the relative position of that item in the range.<br>Q: The MATCH function syntax is MATCH(lookup_value, lookup_array, [match_type])<br>R: All the arguments in a MATCH() function are required.<br>Which of the following statement(s) is/are true",
    "OP1": "Only Q",
    "OP2": "All P, Q, R",
    "OP3": "Only P and R",
    "OP4": "Only P and Q",
    "Answer": 4
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which among the following statements is incorrect about Central Processing Unit?",
    "OP1": "Control Unit controls the order in which instructions enter and leave the processor and how the instructions are executed.",
    "OP2": "Arithmetic Logic Unit is responsible for taking the input, converting it into a signal, and storing it for further processing.",
    "OP3": "Arithmetic Logic Unit is also known as the mathematical brain of a computer.",
    "OP4": "Control Unit directs and manages operation sequences.",
    "Answer": 2
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which among the following registers in Instruction Cycle holds the last instruction fetched?",
    "OP1": "Memory Address Register (MAR)",
    "OP2": "Instruction Register (IR)",
    "OP3": "Program Counter (PC)",
    "OP4": "Memory Buffer Register (MBR)",
    "Answer": 2
  },
  {
    "Question": "In Gmail, what do you use when you receive mail and want to send the mail in response to the same mail and to the original sender only?",
    "OP1": "Forward",
    "OP2": "Both Reply and Forward",
    "OP3": "Reply All",
    "OP4": "Reply",
    "Answer": 4
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is not a magnetic disk?",
    "OP1": "Disk pack",
    "OP2": "DVD",
    "OP3": "Winchester disk",
    "OP4": "Zip disk",
    "Answer": 2
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following buttons are present in the Quick Access Toolbar by default in MS-Word 2010?",
    "OP1": "Undo, Redo, Name",
    "OP2": "Undo, Redo, Cut",
    "OP3": "Paste, Redo, Copy",
    "OP4": "Save, Undo, Redo",
    "Answer": 4
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which among the following statements is incorrect?",
    "OP1": "Memory is required in the webserver to downloading anything.",
    "OP2": "Uploading is a procedure for copying data from the device to the webserver.",
    "OP3": "Data travels from user's device to the web server while uploading.",
    "OP4": "Downloading is a procedure of copying files from the webserver to the machine.",
    "Answer": 1
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following Internet protocol specifies how data is exchanged over the Internet and how it should be broken into IP packets?",
    "OP1": "PPP",
    "OP2": "HTTP",
    "OP3": "TCP",
    "OP4": "SMTP",
    "Answer": 3
  }
]